Hello programmer, welcome back to today's another tutorial topic. So today here is the MongoDB indexing
using for the MongoDB shell, okay. So in this tutorial I can explore for how to improve query
performance by creating index on the MongoDB collections, okay. So now perfectly ensure the
connected MongoDB instance appropriate database. So now I can just here perfectly connect this
MongoDB shell, my database instead, okay. So now I can go for here. Now create for the first
example. So here first define for the single field image, okay. So now just go here and first of all,
I can just save my database for students inside first of all, I can just use the TV and now
inside for the collections name for the students and dot here use for create. So define
perfectly, this third one is the pre index scale. Now here first of all create dependencies
and also the curly brackets. So use the name and one, okay. So here this index for
commonly square the single field image of the name field, the collections. So now here completely
done and press the enter and you can see here this underscore for the one, this acknowledgement,
this expression, the single field index, okay. Next step here I can create for the compound index,
okay. So here I can just create. So first of all here we can type for the DB dot,
use for here the collections name, suppose like students dot, use for here perfectly just now
this on creating the index, okay. So now create for the parenthesis and also the curly brackets.
So here first of all, I'll create for the first column, the age is one, okay. And also here
define for the city. So city is created the decrement one, okay. So this comment. So now created
the compound index on the s and the city field in the collections, okay. Now just execute this
comment and you can see the comment is one and the city increment on, okay. So the acknowledgement
is working and creation of the compound index, okay. And the next system here also used for
another topic for here, creating the unique index, okay. So now just trying. So first of all,
here I can type for the DB dot here I can type the, so now just here I can check in this one.
So here I can choose to do, okay. So also here I can use for the create index, okay.
And now in this inside, first I will create here, here I can create the parenthesis and also create
the curly brackets. And in this inside define for completely, email is one, okay. And next,
the prepare for another curly bracket and type for the unit function, okay. So
UN IQ, okay. The perfectly explained for the unique and this the true statement, okay.
So this is the common unique index only email in to my here the field in the collections,
okay. So now just I can execute this and you can see the ID for here the email entered.
You can see, so you can see here these
first one is this, the Johan, the example,
the block and you can see the several results about here.
I can use the synchronous not done, okay. So now I can go for another topic,
just create here and use for the text index. Okay. So now first of all here I can define for the
DE, the students for the collections name and here create for this is the create for the index
and here I can create for the parenthesis and also create the curly brackets instead I can create
for the description, okay. So now it is perfectly described this description, okay.
So the description now that I can create for the double quotation and
in front I can just type the text columns, okay. So you can see here perfectly created this
command and now I can just execute now and you can see this is completely created this called
the MongoDB acknowledgement index successfully threshold for here, okay. So I hope you perfectly
understand and you can see I have perfectly using now, so I can just find all the index document.
So defined point here the DB dot the students dot user the find function, okay.
And you can see here the old data and here you can see perfectly. So here I can perfectly work
with statement and you can perfectly use for the index operation, okay. So thank you for watching
and happy coding.